hey guys welcome to Rosie's dessert spot
in this tutorial I'll be teaching you
how to make this unicorn
cake I have a 7in cake that's already
been filled and stacked I'm creating the
crumb coat here starting at the very top
pushing it out to the sides and keeping
my spatula nice and flat as I turn the
turntable and then apply another thin
coat around the outside of my cake to
trap in any
crumbs take your bench scraper go around
the cake to smooth it off a little bit
clear up the top bring that lier
frosting to the center and then
refrigerate for 20 minutes before you
add on your final layer of
frosting here I've added some at the
very top and the bottom adding at least
like a good centimet worth and we'll be
taking it off anyway so the more you
start with usually the neater your cake
will be at the end cuz you're not
filling in holes here and there flatten
it out at the top go around the cake
quickly to move the buttercream around
in those holes and then slowly to give
it a nice smooth
finish clear up the top again and and
then pop that into the freezer for 10
minutes to
set now ready to decorate I've got a 1M
tip and I'm just adding dollops here and
there just randomly on the cake and some
rosettes as
well to make the double toned frosting I
have some pink buttercream on one side
of my Piping Bag and on the other side I
filled in with some yellow
buttercream I did the same for my P for
my purple and blue as well and I'm
adding dollops and rosettes Just Between
the pink ones cuz you want want the
colors to be um random and state you
don't want too much of the same color in
one area so that's why I did um bits and
pieces here and there make sure the main
is traveling in a diagonal line that way
you can see it from the front of the
cake and then for the very front of the
cake I've added a rosette as The Fringe
and I've gone in to fill in any space
with some more pink buttercream
then to create the horn I have some gold
colored fondant that I've used um a
merry color gold gel food color to color
it in make two carrots and then press
them together so they stick and then
roll it from the base so I'm just
twisting it and then as I'm twisting I'm
moving closer and closer to the tip of
the
[Music]
horn you can make it as tight or as
Loose as you
like I made it just a little bit tighter
and then with the knife I'm cutting off
the base to the length of the horn that
I
need pop a large skewer into the base
and have it standing on a styrofoam mold
as you paint it to create this paint I
used champagne gold by creative cake
decorating and I added in some rose
water you could also use vodka or lemon
juice some people even use vinegar to
create the
paint and make sure to fill in those
Nook and crannies especially where it's
twisted cuz you um it might be left bare
so be sure to brush into those
spaces pop it into the center of your
cake and I've used the scissors to help
press it all the way
down just like so and then to create the
ears I have two white fondant balls and
I just uh making a bit of a cave kind of
indent in the center pointing the ears
just massaging it until it's nice and
pointed and then flattening the bottom
as
well this is a rose water that I used
it's uh creative cake it's cake
decorators rose water I bought this at
bake
boss and I'm just painting in the middle
of each
ear another really good brand if you
can't find the creative cake decorating
stuff is
ROM they make very nicely pigmented dust
as well that are edible you might want
to read the packaging but most of them
are non-toxic and
edible and then pop a skewer into the
bottom of each ear and allow that to
rest overnight to dry
out pop them onto the sides of your cake
well beside the horn and then again I'm
using my scissors to help help press it
deep into the
cake for The Last Detail I'm adding on
the eyes I've created these little
Cutters for the eyes um to cut out black
fondant but you could always roll logs
of black fondant and stick it onto the
cake you can paint eyes directly onto
the cake as well here I'm applying a
little bit of water to stick it
on and you're done
and that's how you make a full-sized
unicorn cake I do have other tutorials
showing you how to do this but in
miniature form if you guys would like to
see those tutorials I'll leave it in
Link in the description box below this
video but I hope you guys enjoyed this
one all the same it was definitely
really really fun to make and if you do
give it a go do let me know and send me
some photos I would love to see your
Creations thanks again for tuning in and
I'll catch you guys next time